hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TSA automation playlist so
continuing with our topic on the test
automation obstacles now we are going to
look at an obstacle where we need to
drag a particular image from a left to
write box so here you can see uh we need
to drag this particular image so we need
to drag this and put it here and that
will complete top ccle okay so it's
basically the drag and drop
functionality and this is provided out
of the box by tosa so let's see how we
can use this so to make this a little
easier I have already scanned the module
uh it's nothing specific okay so you
just need to select the particular image
which we want to drag and then we need
to select the element which is like a
Dev element okay so this is the dev
element where we need to drag this
particular uh bot picture right so these
are the two elements which uh we need to
uh scan and create a module which I have
already done okay and then uh let's go
ahead and create our test case so here
uh we are going to create our new test
case and uh we are going to rename this
based on this obstacle
number okay and then uh we are going to
use this particular module
here okay so now in the test steps uh we
need to drag and drop right so we need
to drag this particular tosot image okay
so to do this uh we need to use a
predefined uh expression or function
which is already available in tosa which
can perform the drag operation okay and
for that we need to use the curly braces
and then uh we have to type drag so as
you can see uh here is the syntax uh it
is just within the curly braces drag and
then it selects the object for
repositioning uh the respective object
must support drag and drop operations
okay so if you're trying to drag any
particular element it will not work it
should support the drag and drop
operation right okay so so this is what
uh we need to enter here in the value
okay the action mode will be input and
then uh we need to drop it into this
particular element so we will be using
again a expression which is called drop
so this basically will insert an object
uh that was previously selected with the
drag functionality so we are going to uh
write the drop expression here and the
action mode will still be input so this
is all we need to do here in order to
drag a particular object and drop it
into another object right so let's go
ahead and test it out if it works as
expected or
not so as you can see uh tosa is
dragging that particular image and then
putting it inside the Box okay so which
is the expected behavior and that's how
we can solve this particular automation
problem where we have to drag a
particular element from one position to
another position okay and this is
provided out of the box by
tosa that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video